Guide to the Billie Carr political papers, 1956-2003 MS 373
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Billie Carr political papers
1956-2003
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Carr, Billie
MS 373
12 Linear Feet (23 boxes)
The papers of Billie Carr, political organizer in the liberal wing of the Democratic Party, include correspondence, office files, photographs, and memorabilia pertaining to her work in the Harris County Democrats, Texas Democrats, Democratic National Committee, New Democratic Coalition, and Billie Carr & Associates.
Biographical Note
Billie McClain Carr (later known as "The Godmother" for her work on behalf of the liberal wing of the Democratic Party) was born in Houston, Texas, June 1, 1928. She grew up near downtown Houston, graduated from Sam Houston High School in 1946, and married three months later; she had three sons, and over the years took courses at South Texas College and the University of Houston.
Carr's activities as a political organizer began in 1952, when political issues in Texas stirred her to run for Democratic chairman of her precinct and she unexpectedly won. Soon afterward she became a protégé of Frankie Randolph, a leader and benefactress of liberal causes who helped found the Harris County Democrats (a liberal precinct organization) in 1953. She taught Carr the art of grass roots political organizing, and over time Carr assumed a leadership role in Harris County Democrats and began to establish a statewide reputation as an organizer, convention strategist, and spokesperson for the statewide liberal coalition.
In 1954 Carr was elected a member from her precinct to the Harris County Democratic Executive Committee, serving in that capacity until 1972; she was also Harris County's member on the Texas State Democratic Executive Committee from 1964 to 1966. She was a leader in efforts to achieve proportional liberal participation in presidential conventions and became nationally known in the Democratic Party for taking a rump delegation to the 1968 Democratic Convention in Chicago, an action which helped initiate a party-wide set of reforms abolishing the use of the unit rule by which conservative Democrats had been able to minimize the election of liberals as delegates to presidential conventions.
As a liberal activist and strategist, Carr also fought for civil rights. She protested the Vietnam War and fought for women's rights in the 1970s, and for gay rights in the 1980s. She helped organize the 1966 campaign leading to the election of Barbara Jordan, the first black woman elected to the Texas Senate, and was later described by U. S. Rep. Mickey Leland as "the grand old lady of liberal politics" for her efforts in helping a number of minority candidates (including himself) win political office. She later established a business, Billie Carr & Associates, specializing in campaign and other political services.
In 1972 Carr was elected to serve as a member of the Democratic National Committee (a position she held until 2000); there she was elected "whip" for the progressive-reform caucus and in June 1981 was elected chair of the newly-formed Progressive-Liberal Caucus. At various periods she also served on the Credentials Committee, the Platform Advisory Committee on Older Citizens, and the Executive Committee.
Billie Carr died in Houston on September 9, 2002.
Scope and Contents
The Billie Carr Papers total 12 linear feet of material, arranged in 22 boxes and dated 1956-2003. Materials include correspondence, office files, photographs, and memorabilia pertaining to her liberal activist work in the Harris County Democrats, Texas Democrats, Democratic National Committee, New Democratic Coalition, and Billie Carr & Associates. Correspondents such as local and national level political figures include Bob Bullock, President Jimmy Carter, President Bill Clinton, Vice President Al Gore, Ed Cogburn, Chris Dixie, Calvin Guest, Sen. Edward Kennedy, Mickey Leland, and Robert Strauss. Subjects of correspondence range from specific political issues to brief social notes.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Acquisition Information
The original collection of Billie Carr's papers was received from Billie Carr in March 1983. Addenda were received 1988 and 2004 from Prof. Chandler Davidson of Rice University;, 2002 from Stacey McLain; and 2003 from Jennifer Carr.
General
Original folder titles and office file organization (as indicated by color-coded folders) have been retained. Loose material (the bulk of the collection) has been organized to conform as closely as possible to the method of arrangement evidently intended.
Related Material
Walter Gardner Hall Papers, 1923-1979, MS 280, Woodson Research Center
Frankie Carter Randolph Papers, ca. 1900-1975, MS 372, Woodson Research Center
Texas Politics Oral History Program, 1973-1994, MS 259, Woodson Research Center
Albert Thomas papers, 1937-1965, MS262, Woodson Research Center
Index Terms
Subjects
Women; Women social reformers; Women -- Political activity; Political parties; Women and democracy; Politics and government; Civil rights
Document Types
scrapbooks; photographs; clippings (information artifacts); invitations; corrrespondence
Places
United States; Texas; Texas -- Harris County
Subjects (Persons)
Strauss, Robert S.; Bullock, Bob--Correspondence; Cogburn, Ed; Carr, Billie; Clinton, Bill (William J.); Dixie, Chris; Gore, Albert; Guest, Calvin; Kennedy, Edward M. (Edward Moore), Senator; Leland, Mickey; Carter, Jimmy
Subjects (Corporations)
Billie Carr & Associates; Democratic National Committee.; Democratic Party (Tex.); New Democratic Coalition (U.S.); Harris County Democrats (Harris County, Tex.)
- Series I. Personal Files, 1969-2003, 1.5 linear ft., 3 boxes
  - Subseries A: Biographical Material
    - Biographical material (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Research Proposal, Center for the American Woman and Politics; March 27, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Book Stuff [for proposed autobiography] (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Billie Carr – Scrapbook [contents removed from ring binder, two photos removed to Photographs] (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Memorials and tributes from family and friends (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B: Correspondence
    - Billie Carr Personal Incoming; 1981-82 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Billie Carr Personal (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence – Personal – BC Fundraising (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Personal – Love Hate Mail (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Love Hate Mail, 1973-78 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Billie Carr – Outgoing; 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 1991-92 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Letterhead (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Inauguration [President Jimmy Carter, Vice President Walter Mondale] (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Letters from Candidates, etc. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Issues (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Gays (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - National Women's File (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Racism Workshop; 1997 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence – prominent political figures (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bob Bullock (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Clinton [President William J.] (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Ed Cogburn (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Robert Kennedy, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Frankie Randolph (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1983-84 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1987-88 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1990-91 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1993-94 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1995-96 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 2000-2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Newsletters (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous publications (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Clippings (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Billie Carr – News Files, 1986-96 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Series II. Harris County Democrats, 1956-2003, 3.5 linear ft., 7 boxes.
  - Subseries A: Harris County Democratic Executive Committee
    Scope and Contents note
    This subseries includes correspondence and general chronological office files.
    - Harris County Democratic Executive Committee By-Laws (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Harris County Democratic Executive Committee Membership Lists, 1973- 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - General – Minutes [Executive Committee]; 1971 – 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Filing Fees 1974; Democratic Executive Committee – B. W. [Bill Williams] (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Harris County Democratic Executive Committee, 1978-82 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Harris County Democratic Executive Committee, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Democratic Executive Committee Questionnaire (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Harris County Democratic Executive Committee Sheet [Sub-Committee Solicitation Form] (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Harris County Democratic Executive Committee – undated material (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Subseries B: Harris County Democrats – Correspondence
    - Harris County Democrats – History and Constitution (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Harris County Democrats General – Correspondence 1972-73 Outgoing (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Harris County Democrats General – Correspondence 1972-74 Incoming (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Harris County Democrats, Correspondence, 1974-75 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Harris County Democrats, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Harris County Democrats, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Harris County Democrats, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Harris County Democrats, Correspondence, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - HCD – Outgoing; 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Billie Carr Incoming; 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Harris County Democrats, Correspondence, 1980-87 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Harris County Democrats, Correspondence, 1990-96 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Harris County Democrats, Correspondence, 1997-99 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Harris County Democrats, Correspondence, 2000-2002 and undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Subseries C. Harris County Democrats - Subject Files
    This subseries includes formats such as brochures, political flyers, scattered correspondence, and notes.
    - Activities in Houston; 1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - ADA List [Americans for Democratic Action] (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Affirmative Action – 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Application for Executive Committee (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Attendance Lists; 1974-76 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Attorneys (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Billie Carr Birthday Bash – Correspondence; 1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Billie Carr: Don't Default to the Bastards: Organize! (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Billie Carr Expense Fund (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Billie Carr's Political Directory (four folders) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Brochures, handbooks, organizational material (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - 1980 Budget File (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Canvassing instructions (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Cardpushers Captain's Instruction Sheet (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Carter Presidential Campaign, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Castillo [Leonel]; 1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Celebration of Peoples Committee, Bette Graham, Chairman; April 1975 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Challenge Committee - Rules of Procedure, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Changes to computerized mailing lists, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Churches in Houston (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Citizens against Nuclear War (CAN), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - City Candidates, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - City Election Results, 1977, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - City of Houston General Election Results, November 4, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - City Officials, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Committees – HCD 1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Contested Precinct Races by Senate District, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Convention Delegates by Senate District - 1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Counties by State Senate District, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - County Incoming Mail, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Delegates – Seventh State Senate District (no date) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 1982 Delegates Allocated to State (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 1982 Delegates Alternates (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Democratic Committeemen and Committeewomen, July 1, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Democratic County Chairperson Election, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Democratic Delegate Questionnaire (Jimmy Carter years) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Democratic Fun Fest – 1977, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Democratic Party Precinct Forms – 1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Democratic Party of Texas – Precinct Convention Minutes, May 1978 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Democratic Precinct Convention Handbook, compiled by Carr and Hauge (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Democratic Primary Election Results, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Democratic Socialists Notes, May-December 1982 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Democrats – Clubs [Houston]; no date (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - District 7 Club; 1977-78 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - District 7 Coalition; 1976 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - District 7 Precinct Chairmen; no date (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - District 7 Precinct Convention Minutes; 1978 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - District 7 Senatorial District Convention Minutes, May 1978 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - State Senatorial District 9 Delegates (no date) (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - District 13 Convention Minutes, May 1978 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - District 13 Democrats (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - District materials (miscellaneous) (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Districts within each County; 1981-82 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Ed Cogburn Campaign; 1993-94 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Election code (1973?) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Election Judges – Additions/Replacements January 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Endorsements; 1997 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Filing Form – 1978 [Harris County] (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Fort Bend County [and Harris County]; 1978 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Free Choice Democrats (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - General Election Results – 1974 [Harris County] (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - General Election Voters Guide, November 2, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - General – Reference Lists 1972-73 Liberal Committeemen (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - General Reference Lists, Guides; 1972-73 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Get-Out-the-Vote Program, Proposal for; 1978 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - GOTV '88 [Get-Out-the-Vote] (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Guidelines for Voter Registration (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Hand Tabulation of HCD Data (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Happy Hour labels candidates; February 24, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Harris County Candidates in the May 6, 1978 Democratic Primary (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Harris County Council of Organizations; 1980 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Harris County Democrat newsletter; October 15, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Harris County Democratic Party, 1988-89 [removed from yellow binder] (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Harris County Democratic Party, State Senate District 17, Precinct Workbook; September 6, 1998 [removed from binder] (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Harris County Democrats "Demo Activists" [list] (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Harris County Democrats District Convention Minutes; May 13, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Harris County Democrats – Filings '78 [1978 Democratic Primary] (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Harris County Democrats Newsletters; 1977, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Harris County Democrats Nominating Committee, 1977-79 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Harris County Democrats office space (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Harris County Democrats organizational material (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Harris County Democrats Re-Organizational Plan [Pre-1978] (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - HCD Bob Hauge (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - HCD Calendar of Events; 1982 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - HCD Office Projects (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - HCD Poll (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - HCD Screening Report, October 5, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Headquarters [Harris County Democrats]; November 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Houston Independent School District; 1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Houston Transportation Advisory Group; 1977-78 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Interview responses for Harris County Democrats Planning Committee survey (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Inventory of files [incomplete] (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Issues – County; February 1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Judges Who Cancelled; 1982 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - League of Women Voters Precinct Guide (1977) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Letters from John Odam; 1982 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Letters from Mike Andrews; 1982 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Liberal Executive Committeemen; March 1977 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - List of Harris County Elected Officials; no date (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Lists – Computer [precincts]; August 1997 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Manual of Voting Precincts; 1976, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Moderate Progressive [MOD/PRO] Convention Caucus; 1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Names – County; 1981-82 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - New Voter Registration; 1978 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Newsletters (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - 1974 – Offices open for elections (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Open Party Caucus – September 1974 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Organizational material (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Party Officials [Democratic Executive Committeeman Candidates]; no date (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Party Stuff; 1997-98 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Payroll for period 10/23 through 11/1 [1976] (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Petitions supporting Carr's re-election to Democratic National Committee (c. 1976) (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Phone Banks – Democratic Party; 1978 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Political Advertisements from HCD (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Political Directory, 1992-93 [removed from purple binder] (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Political Directory [incomplete] (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Polling Places – 1976 General Election (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Polling Places, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Polling Places of an Official Nature, Schools, Parks, Fire Stations [removed from corrugated folder-file], labeled as follows:
      - Polling places (general); 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Aldine ISD [Independent School District]; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Alief ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Channelview ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Clear Creek ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Cypress-Fairbanks ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Deer Park; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Fire Departments – Houston City; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Goose Creek ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Houston Independent School District (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Huffman ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Humble ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Katy ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Klein ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - La Porte ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Libraries – Harris County (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Libraries, Houston (City); 1982 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - North Forest ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Parks – Houston (City); 1982 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Pasadena ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Sheldon ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Spring ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Spring Branch ISD; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - Primary Election Expenses and Estimates; 1980, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - Voting Machines; 1982 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Precinct Caucus Attendance Sheets [blank forms] (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Precinct Chairmen, not Harris County (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Precinct Chairmen by Legislative District, January 1974 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Precinct Changes for 1978 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Precinct Judges; 1978 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Precinct Organizing Manuals; c. 1956, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Precinct Materials, 1972-2002 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Precinct Materials, undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Precinct 316 List of Voter Registrations (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Precincts by Race, Ethnicity (no date) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Precincts by Senate Districts; March 1982 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Precincts – HCD Breakdown, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Precincts within the Houston City Limits (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Public poll for city elections (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Republican candidates [Harris County]; May 1974 primary (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Results of Primary – 1974 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Road Maps – Houston (1974, 1977, 1980) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - "Samples" (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Screening Committee 1974 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Screening Committee 1976 – Primary Election (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Screening for Democratic Primary Election, May 3, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Senate District 13 – 1982 Delegates (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Share in American Democracy brochure; 1958 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Sign-in Sheets (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Steering Committee 1975 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Summary of Vote Projections – Allee (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Tally Fri 10/29 [Telephone survey, 1976] (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Taxation, City of Houston (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Texas ACORN (Association for Community Organizations for Reform Now] (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Texas Democrats Attendance Sheets; 1976-78 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Texas Democrats Senatorial District Information (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Texas Senate District 7 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - "Things to Do" and tablet of personal reminders (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Voter Registration; 1976 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Women in Action; 1982 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Women's Advocates, Inc. (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Women's Center; 1982 [Houston Area] (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Women's Political Caucus; 1982 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Women's Rights; 1982 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - World Map, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 32)
- Series III. Texas Democrats, 1971-2000, 2.5 linear ft., 5 boxes
  - Subseries A: State Democratic Executive Committee (SDEC), 1974-2000; 0.40 lin. feet, .8 box.
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1976-77 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1980-84 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1994, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1997-99 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - SDEC Badges – Order Form (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - SDEC Committees; 1998-2000 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - SDEC Committees and General Duties (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - SDEC Committees and General Rules (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - SDEC Incoming; 1981-1983 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - SDEC Proxy Form (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - SDEC Radio Spots; 1982 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Meetings of SDEC; 1981-1983 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Mod-Pro [Moderate-Progressive] Caucus SDEC Telephone List (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Subseries B: General Correspondence, 1971-2000; 0.75 linear feet, 1.2 boxes
    - Texas Democrats – History and Structure (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - State Incoming; 1981-82 (Box 11, Folder 21)